这不是我们所能驯服的严寒
This cold isn't something we can tame.
是我们让我们的气候成了这样
We did this to our climate.
只有地球本身能重启她温暖的心
Now only the Earth herself can restart her warm heart.
我相信我们能再次找到她的脉搏
I believe we can find her pulse again.
我最害怕的
And my biggest fear...
不是死在外面
isn't dying out here.
而是我们中的冷血之人会在我还没证明希望前
It's that the cold-hearted among us will crush that hope
就将其浇灭
before I can prove it.
淡定  淡定
All right, all right.
布雷斯劳尔研究站
Breslauer Research Station.
温度为零下122.6度
The temperature is minus 122.6 Celcius.
我在海拔3400米上
I'm 11,000 feet above sea level,
岌岌可危
dangling from a thin umbilical.
距离雪国列车很遥远
Many miles from Snowpiercer...
1034节车厢
1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第六集
"远离雪国列车"
终于找到你了
There you are.
好的
Okay.
妈妈  你在吗
Mommy? Are you there?
我床下有怪物
There's a monster under my bed.
妈妈
Mommy.
你在哪  妈妈
Where are you? Mommy?
妈妈  有怪物
Mommy, there's a monster.
妈妈
Mom?
我找到了两具在大冰封时
I found the bodies of two of the scientists
驻扎此地的科学家的尸体
stationed here at the Freeze...
一个男性  头部中弹
one male, shot in the head...
另一个为女性  割腕
the other a woman who slit her wrists.
面对世界末日这里一定是个可怕的地方
Must've been a grim place to face the end of the world.
但天一亮  我就得恢复这里的电力
But at first light, I have to power it back up,
把我的电池加入太阳能电池阵
patch my batteries into the solar array.
然后我就回去
Then I'll go back down
找我的雪橇和食物
for the sled I left behind with my rations.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
在过去
In the old time,
未来似乎有多个层面
the future seemed multifaceted.
我们有事业  家庭  个人抱负
We had careers, families, personal aspirations,
有想去的地方  想见的朋友  遗愿清单
places to go, friends to see, bucket lists--
我们认为理所当然的人类梦想的嗡嗡声
the hum of human dreams we took for granted.
但我们其实是在梦游
But we were sleepwalking,
距离把这些所有可能的未来
just one step away from trading all those possible futures
换成大冰封的共同命运只有一步之遥
for the shared fate of the Freeze.
我就知道你会在这里
I thought I'd find you here.
我们创造的这东西真美
It's a beautiful thing we've created.
这要看我们如何定义"创造"
Depends how we define "Created."
你或许值得一点肯定
Well, I suppose you might deserve a little credit.
你是胶水
You're the glue.
你把雪国列车的所有部件拼凑到了一起
You put all Snowpiercer's pieces together.
她属于我也属于你
She's just as much yours as she is mine.
你绝不会听到我当众说出这话
And you will never hear me repeat that in public.
你的投资者想听什么你就说什么  约瑟夫
Whatever your investors need to hear, Joseph.
他们听到了
Oh, they heard it.
我的永动机
My "Engine Eternal."
这要看我们如何定义"永动"
Depends how we define "Eternal."
好了
Now, now...
别毁了这一刻的气氛
let's not ruin the moment.
不可能的
That's not possible,
因为现在
because now...
我们终于能驱动她了
we finally get to drive her.
好
Okay.
妈妈  食物在哪
Mommy? Where's the food?
你去商店了吗
Did you go to the store?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
原来那条手臂在这
Ah, so that's where that arm went.
你疲惫不堪
You're exhausted.
还是山上稀薄的空气
Or is it this thin mountain air
让你的大脑出现了幻觉
that's playing tricks on your mind?
你的供给都被雪崩埋了
So, with your supplies under that avalanche,
你只剩下一袋口粮
all you have left is one ration pack...
一包本给你的糖
one bag of sweeties from Ben...
和一条手臂
and an arm.
我不需要那条手臂也能应付过去
I'll manage without the arm.
真的吗  那似乎有点乐观
Really? That seems a bit optimistic.
根据日志
According to the logbooks,
外面那些年轻的食人族
our fine young cannibals out there
是气候科学家
were climate scientists.
他们在大冰封刚开始时出来
They came out at the start of the Freeze
寻找在CW7中存活下来的办法
looking for a way to survive CW-7--
好吧  是在其影响下存活
well, the effects of it.
显然他们没成功
Apparently they didn't succeed,
不过她倒是撑了五个月之久
though she did hang on for five months.
30天后  雪国列车返回
我只需要撑一个月
I only have to make it one.
不敢看你前任们的容貌吗
Afraid to look upon your predecessors' visage?
我只是不想看见
Just don't want to see it.
因为他们生前有个小女儿
Because they had a little girl.
你变得...多愁善感了  梅兰妮
You've acquired a... sentimental streak, Melanie.
你天真  有雄心壮志时更有用
You're a lot more useful when you're naive and ambitious.
雪国列车现在应该
Snowpiercer should be releasing
正在发射第一批气象气球
the first of her weather balloons right about now.
我...
I am...
给气候模拟程序打补丁
patched into the climate-modeling program.
只需从天线电塔连上气球
Just need to link to the balloon from the radio tower.
给它提供足够的数据点来推断出一个模型
Feed it enough data points to extrapolate a model.
要说有谁能拼凑出
Well, if anyone can kludge together
一个试验性的气候模型  那一定是你  亲爱的
a heuristic climate model, it's you, my dear.
不过可惜你得依靠本
Shame you have to rely on Ben, though, hmm?
和他的气球
And his balloons.
还有那个西班牙佬  拜托
And that Spaniard. Come on.
你明知道哈维是哥伦比亚人
You know Javi's Colombian.
也许你会在那里找到我们传说中的伊甸园
Oh, well, perhaps that's where you'll find our fabled Eden.
他事前不知道我们要偷走你的火车
And he didn't know we were stealing the train from you.
事实上  我们行驶了两天
Actually, we were two days down the track
他才发觉
before he figured it out.
这很不错  对吧
This is nice, isn't it?
辩论
Jousting?
能让你忘记饥饿
Keeps your mind off the hunger.
太好了
Yes!
第一次联系
看起来到伊甸园还长路漫漫
Seems a long way to Eden.
算是个开始
It's a start.
饼干丢了吗
Lost your biscuit?
我肯定是吃了
I must've eaten it.
我知道你不相信
I know you don't believe that.
是啊
No.
我没吃饼干
I didn't eat that cracker.
那么问题来了
Which begs the question...
谁吃了
who did?
或许我们的食人族饿了
Perhaps our cannibals are hungry.
要不就是你在失去心智  工程师
Either that, or you're cracking up, Engineer.
告诉我你不会真的要这么做
Tell me you aren't really doing this.
我们需要这么多东西  你却在打造你的妓院
With everything else we need, you're working on your brothel?
不是妓院  一辆夜车
Not a brothel. A Nightcar!
这趟列车现在是拯救人类的方舟
This train is now an ark for humanity,
不是满足你个人的奢愿
not your personal indulgences.
不能一举两得吗
Can't it be both?
台上艺术
Art onstage...
后方娱乐
and entertainment in the back.
这能让灵魂延续  梅兰妮
It sustains the soul, Melanie...
而且这是个放气阀  能管住大家
and it's a release valve to keep everyone under control.
你浪费在这上面的资源
The resources that you're wasting on this
能够喂饱二十人  而我们需要这些人
could sustain 20 more people that we're going to need.
票务部说你从乘客名单中删掉了
Ticketing says you removed half of my geneticists
我一半的遗传学家
from the passenger list.
-我们还有更重要的事要优先考虑  -比如呢
- We have more important priorities. - Like what?
比如你的安保吗
Like...your security?
我向你保证  所有枪支都会被没收
I promised you-- all guns will be confiscated
从列车上扔出去
and thrown from the train.
但守卫能保持秩序
But the Jackboots will keep order.
三千个人挤在16公里长的钢管里
3,000 souls stuffed into a 10-mile steel tube--
你觉得他们会突然之间
you think they're all gonna suddenly
和谐相处吗
start singing "Kumbaya"?
我觉得如果我们要拯救人类
I think that if we are going to save humankind,
我们需要真正知道如何拯救人类的人
we need people who actually know how to save humankind.
-要多少  -六个遗传学家
- How many? - Six geneticists...
和他们的亲属  一共12人
and next of kin--12 total.
-去掉12个守卫  -我去掉六个
- Just cut 12 Jackboots. - I'll cut six.
约瑟夫  拜托
Joseph, please...
还有比秩序更重要的东西
There are gonna be more important things than order.
没有什么比秩序更重要
Nothing's more important than order.
你真的相信自己说的鬼话吗
Do you even believe in any of this?
显然我让你工作太辛苦了
Clearly, I've been working you too hard...
所以我原谅你刚才说的一切
which is why I will forgive what you just said.
雪国列车只有一位首席工程师  她的创造者
Snowpiercer has only one Head Engineer--her creator.
她听我的命令运行
She runs on my order.
如果你无法接受这点  那么
And if you can't accept that, then...
你的家人可以不用上车了
your family can stay behind.
听明白了吗
Is that clear?
你没法
You can't--
你没法粉饰世界末日  梅兰妮
you can't sugarcoat the end of the world, Melanie.
不是一切都会没事的
Not everything's going to be fine,
但是  我向你保证
but I promise you...
你会活下来的
you will survive.
谢谢你  约瑟夫
Thank you, Joseph.
我来到这已经十天了
It's been ten days since I arrived.
如果我有食物的话
If I had food...
这会是一个光鲜亮丽的报告
This would be a glowing report.
每一次新的探测  系统就会收集更多的数据
With each new probe, the system has more data,
我逐渐搭建出一个气候模型
and I coax a climate model.
"画作"还远未完成
The picture's far from complete.
现在问题是
Now the question...
我是否能活着完成它
is whether I can survive long enough to finish painting it.
饥饿很难受吧
Hunger's a bitch, ain't it?
你稍微感受到了一点
You're getting a little taste
你对我们在车尾做的事
of what you did to us back in the Tail.
我不是要戳痛处
Not to rub it in.
不  你就是在戳我痛处
No, you're rubbing it in.
是啊  我就是
Yeah, I am.
那些尸体可能有点冻伤
Those bodies might have a little freezer burn,
但是最好不要介意
but I wouldn't let that put you off.
我不做评价
No judgment here.
我不会诉诸于食人肉
I'm not resorting to cannibalism.
你试试没有食物再过一个周再说
Give yourself another week with no food.
我有食物
I've got food.
你知道这很疯狂  对吧
You know this is crazy, right?
是的
Yep.
已经过去七年了  怎么会有东西还活着
It's been seven years. How could anything be alive?
是不该有
It shouldn't be.
所以  要么是外面确实有什么东西存活了下来
So either something did survive out there,
是个奇迹  要么
which is a miracle, or...
我疯了
I'm losing it?
是你说的  我可没说
You said it, not me.
非常好
Oh! Very nice.
看上去像是个车尾人会设计出的东西
Looks like something a Tailie would've cooked up.
这就对了
That's what I'm talking about.
我一直在想我发现的那三具尸体
I've been thinking about the three bodies I found.
风流韵事
Torrid affair.
亚瑟是第一个去世的
Arthur was the first to go.
他是那个头盖骨中了一枪的人
The fellow with the bullet in his brainpan.
另两个人除掉了他
The other two got rid of him.
-他是她的丈夫  -真的吗
- He was her husband. - Really?
-那个自杀了的女的  -你怎么发现的
- The woman who killed herself. - How'd you find that out?
他是那个电脑屏保上的男的
He's the guy on the screensaver.
我喜欢这个意外转折
Oh, I like that twist.
-或许他生病了  -没错
- Maybe he got sick. - Yes.
她和另一个人知道他命不久矣
She and the other fellow knew he was a goner.
他多苟延残喘一天
Every day he lingered on was another day
就要多蚕食一天他们所需要的食物
he was consuming food they needed.
所以他们帮他脱离苦海
So they put him out of his misery.
一枪爆头
Shot to the head.
她牺牲了他  梅兰妮
She sacrificed him, Melanie...
就像你牺牲了我一样
Like you did to me.
她做的决定是正确的
She made the right decision.
我就知道你会这么说
I knew you'd say that.
不然她还能怎么做
What else could she do?
他们有上千个人
There's thousands of 'em.
大门需要增援
We need reinforcements at the main gate.
哈维在哪
Where's Javi?
在发动机房
Engine room.
他们是怎么知道发车时间的
How did they find out departure time?
已经零下45了  而且随时会更冷
It's 45 below and getting colder by the minute, you know.
他们还会去哪
Where else are they gonna go?
还是我工程师卡维尔
It's Engineer Cavill again.
我家人乘坐的列车到了吗
Has the transport with my family arrived yet?
他们一上车就立刻通知我
I need to know the moment they're on the train.
列车后方是怎么回事
What the hell's going on downtrain?
-等等  -我和你们说了
- Wait. - I told you.
-能帮我把车尾指挥官找来吗  -你们俩
- Can you get me Tail Command? - Both of you!
-加强戒备  -等一下
- More security! - Hold on.
我们在驶出车站之前就要被人攻占了
We're about to be overrun before we leave the station.
-已接通格雷指挥官  -好
- Commander Grey's on the line. - Right.
是你吗  《血涌雷鸣》再现吗
Is that you, old Blood and Thunder?
美国作家汉普顿·塞兹的一本纪实小说
故事聚焦19世纪美国西部的转变
外面到底是怎么回事
What's the story back there?
防线还能守住  长官
The perimeter fence is holding, sir,
但是人越来越多
but more just keep coming.
我们发射了实弹
We fired live rounds,
但是坚守不了太久
but it won't hold much longer.
如果他们攻破防线  炮火全开
If they break through... you unleash hell on them.
竭尽全力不让他们进入
You do whatever it takes to hold them back.
-明白吗  -是的  长官
- Is that clear? - Yes, sir.
采取一切必要的武力
All necessary force.
各位  最后一辆开往克拉克斯维尔市
Last train to Clarksville, people.
我家人还没上车
My family isn't on board yet.
而且我们还需要三十分钟
And we still need 30 minutes
才能完成引擎循环
to finish cycling up the engine, sir.
这人是谁
Who the hell is this?
我们是科学家  我们有车票
We're scientists! We have tickets!
-你是真的  -是的
- You're real. - Yes!
干得漂亮  梅
Way to go, Mel.
我知道一个烹饪这只母老鼠的好食谱
I know a great recipe for her.
公的
Him.
我有个更好的主意
I have a better idea.
太好了
Frickin' amazing.
这是一个地热出口
It's a geothermal vent.
这些暖气让老鼠活下来了
The warmth kept them alive?
那条裂缝看起来像又多了一条新的裂缝
That fissure looks like it has a fresh crack in it.
肯定是在大冰封的时候裂开的
Must have opened up in the Freeze.
我想你说得对
I bet you're right.
看来老鼠跟着人一起来了
I guess the rats came with the people,
但是它们先找到了这里
but they found it first.
然后你找到了它们
But then you found them.
简直是奇迹
It's a miracle.
是生命  妈妈
It's life, Mom.
好吃
Yum.
在蒸汽孔里躲藏并繁衍了七年
Seven years hiding and procreating in a steam vent,
现在进了我们的肚子
and now straight into our stomachs.
是啊
Yeah, well...
毫不后悔
zero regrets.
你现在幸存几率大多了
I like your chances better now.
蒸汽孔可以给你补充热量
The vent can supplement your heat
让数据库有更多电力
and allow more power for your databases.
我在竭尽全力
Doing everything I can.
不过我们之间还是有很长距离
Still a lot of track between us.
要是没有雪橇你要怎么来见我们
What will you do without your sled to meet us?
我会走回轨道
I'll walk back to the track...
带上电池和硬盘
pack a battery and the hard drive on the sled.
有必要的话我可以往返一次
I could make it there and back if I had to.
妈
Mom?
我现在好想明白了
I think I understand now...
你当初为什么要把我留在芝加哥
Why you had to leave me in Chicago.
你的指令是什么  先生
What are your orders, sir?
他们说他们有票
They say they're ticketed.
他们有芯片
They've got chips!
他们是我的遗传学家
They are my geneticists.
-你答应要让他们上车的  -什么
- You agreed to have them on board, ... - What?
我们需要他们
and we need them.
我答应你可以请六个人
I agreed you could have six.
现在我们需要六个守卫
Right now we need six Jacks more.
没有他们我不走  约瑟夫
I am not going without all of them, Joseph.
知道吗  我们没空争了
You know what? We don't have time to discuss it.
让所有人上车吧
Let's just get everyone on board.
你说得对
You're right.
没时间了
There's no time.
干掉他们
Terminate them.
永远别忘了  梅兰妮
Never forget, Melanie.
列车要听我指挥
The train runs on my order.
预计出发时间
Estimated time of departure?
-28分钟  -好的
- 28 minutes. - Good.
我要去后车了
Now I'm going downtrain.
我们要在主门也开火
And we're going to open fire on the main gate, too.
你只管完成循环
You just finish the damn cycle-up...
准备好出发
and be ready to depart.
会准备好的
She'll be ready.
很好
Good.
我们坐吉普车
We'll take the Jeep.
拜托
Come on.
砰砰声
Ping.
你今天可是够精彩啊  对吗
You're having quite the day, aren't you?
现在你失去了气球数据
Now you've lost your balloon data.
部不不不
No, no, no, no, no!
你现在肯定
I bet you're feeling a bit
跟雪里的那女人感同身受
like our friend out in the snow.
你懂的  那个...
You know, the woman who, uh...
闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
以那样的方式自杀  我逐渐有了尊重
Suicide in that manner, I've--I've grown to respect...
当然取决于周遭状况
depending on the circumstances, of course.
有时候  它会变化
Sometimes it--it transforms.
你在说些什么
What are you even talking about?
你不会明白的
Ah, you wouldn't understand.
但我对她毫无尊重
I've no respect for her, though.
她抛下了她的孩子
She left her child behind, you know.
她那么做是为了和她的孩子在一起
She did it to be with her child,
因为她以为他们会团聚
because she thought that they would be reunited.
多愁善感
Sentimentality.
就跟她无法吃她丈夫的理由一样
Same reason she couldn't eat her husband.
为了什么  她的任务失败
And for what? Her mission failed.
她牺牲了她的家庭  她的人性  一切
She sacrificed her family, her humanity, everything,
就跟你一样
just like you.
这个任务还没完
This mission is not done.
艾莉克斯会在冷锁处见我
Alex is meeting me at the cold lock.
是的  回到艾莉克斯身边
Ah, yes. Get back to Alex.
把她从魔鬼身边救走
Save her from the monster.
我会再抓一只老鼠
I'll catch another rat.
我会再坚持两周  混蛋
I'll make it two more weeks, you sack of shit.
我觉得这很有说服力
I find it telling, this notion
你觉得你比我优秀的观念
you're such a better human than me.
我救了你抛下的女儿
I saved the daughter you left behind.
或许你该感激我
Perhaps a-a little gratitude is in order?
他们应该跟四个警卫在一起
They should be with four bodyguards.
我的家...
My par--
我家长是老人
my parents are elderly.
立刻放下
Drop those, now!
是的  我女儿八岁
Yes, my--my daughter is eight.
如果他们没登记  我需要你去找他们
If they're not checked in, I need you to look for them.
喂  喂
Hello! Hello!
他们应该还没到
I don't think they're here yet.
火车头  回话  火车头  回话
Engine, come in. Engine, come in.
火车头  回话
Engine, come in.
这里是火车头
This is the Engine.
我失去了跟格雷指挥官的联系
I've lost contact with Commander Grey.
我要开车到前车去见他
I'm driving uptrain to see him.
我一下车  就出发
As soon as I get off, we leave.
收到  准备在六分钟后出发
Roger that. Ready to leave in six minutes.
我们可以在一分钟后就走  梅
We can roll in one minute, Mel.
我要过去
I'm going down there.
你必须作出决定马上出发
You have to make the call to go.
艾莉克斯也许正试图上车
Alex might be trying to get on board.
你不能下车  梅
You can't get off this train, Mel.
-我不会让你走  -本  放我走
- I am not leaving you here. - Ben, let me go.
-我必须走  -我们不能让那魔鬼
- I have to go. - We can't let that monster
掌管仅剩的人类
be in charge of what's left of humanity.
你想偷走这列车  拯救未来吗
You want to steal the train and save the future?
我们必须现在就走
We have to go now.
请上车
All aboard.
所有有票的乘客  请上车
All ticketed passengers, please board.
雪国列车会在0点准时出发
Snowpiercer departs at precisely 0000 hours.
松开制动踏板
Release the brake.
解除制动踏板
Disengaging brakes.
雪国列车将在10
Snowpiercer departs in ten...
9  8  7
nine, eight, seven,
6  5
six, five...
-下车  把他们扔下车  -3  2  1秒后
- Off the train! Throw 'em off the train! - Three, two, one...
出发
departure.
接合发动机
Engaging the Engine.
原谅我
Forgive me.
该死
Shit.
太好了
Yeah.
成功了  成功了
It's working. It's working.
该掉头回来了  雪国列车
Time to turn around and hurry back, Snowpiercer.
雪国列车返回
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
雪国列车  回话
Snowpiercer, come in.
你们现在应该进入范围了
You should be in range by now.
收到了吗  我是梅兰妮
Do you copy? It's Melanie.
雪国列车  雪国列车
Snowpiercer, Snowpiercer.
受到了吗
Do you copy?
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
我准备去汇合地点了
I'm prepared to rendezvous for pickup.
本
Ben?
艾莉克斯
Alex?
我拿到了气候模型
I have the climate model.
艾莉
Allie...
我努力了
I tried.
我真的努力了
I r-really tried.
以及...
And...
我以为这次会不一样
I thought this time would be different.
我以为我会回到你身边
I thought I would get back to you.
所以
So...
请原谅我
Please forgive me.
你为我们放弃了一切
You gave up everything for us...
为世界
for the world.
你不必再感到抱歉
You don't have to be sorry anymore...
对我
not to me...
或任何人都不用
not to anyone.
没有你雪国列车不会走到今天
Snowpiercer couldn't have made it this far without you.
你和我也不会有这样的机会
And you and I would never have gotten this chance.
谢谢
Thank you.
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
雪国列车  能听到我吗
Snowpiercer! Do you hear me?
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
你们得慢下来
You need to slow your roll.
你们得慢下来  听到吗
You need to slow your roll! Do you hear me?
停下
Stop!
妈  妈
Mom! Mom!